Quoc-Tin Phan

CONTACT Information Dept. of Information Engineering and Computer

Science

University of Trento, Italy (+39) 3420236513 Via Sommarive (+39) auoctin.phan@unitn.it

9 I-38123 Povo (TN) https://github.com/quoctin

RESEARCH INTERESTS Modern photography is losing its innocency under the presence of an adversary, who can perform sophisticated image manipulations undetectable by human visual system. I am passionate on the exploitation of machine learning and optimization techniques to detect imperceptible patterns, towards protecting and recovering the trustworthiness of digital images.

EDUCATION

Ph.D candidate in ICT, University of Trento, Italy

Nov. 2015 - present

- Expected graduation: Apr. 2019.
- Concentration: Modern digital images are being created, manipulated, and diffused in uncontrolled manners. My Ph.D study focuses on the exploitation of machine learning and optimization techniques towards uncovering digital image provenance.
- Advisors: Assoc. Prof. Giulia Boato and Prof. Francesco G. B. De Natale

Master in CS, University of Science, HCMC, Vietnam Sep. 2011 - Dec. 2013

- Concentration: Searchable encryption based on discrete logarithm problem on matrix group.
- Advisor: Assoc. Prof. Thuc D. Nguyen

Bachelor in CS (Honor program), University of Information Technology, HCMC, Vietnam Sep. 2006 - Dec. 2010

- Thesis: Sync data on parallel channels for distance learning.
- Advisor: Dr. Hong-Hai Dam-Quang

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Research Visiting Student

Sep. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Visual Information Processing and Protection (VIPP)

Department of Information Engineering and Mathematics

University of Siena, Italy

Concentration: Copying the source region and pasting into the target region is an easy-to-perform image manipulation to hide objects or to deceive viewers. My research aims at building an end-to-end system for detecting duplications and disambiguating source-target.

Supervisor: Mauro Barni, Ph.D

Teaching Assistant

Sep. 2017 - Mar. 2018

Multimedia Data Security (Master course), University of Trento

Collaborator in EUREGIO challenge, hosted by University of Trento, Italy, and University of Innsbruck, Austria.

Research Assistant

May. 2011 - Oct. 2015

Faculty of Computer Network and Communication University of Information Technology, HCMC

Supervisor: Hong-Hai Dam-Quang, Ph.D

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Firmware Engingeer

Aotea Global Services Limited

Nov. 2013 - Apr. 2014

Responsibility: developing firmware to function a system involving electronics devices: Arduino boards, Bluetooth, GPS, RF Transceivers.

3D Game Programmer

Aug. 2010 - Apr. 2011

Gameloft Corporation

Responsibility: porting 3D games written in C++ to be runnable on Android platform by using Android NDK.

TECHNICAL SKILLS Programming languages: Python, Matlab, C++, Bash Script Machine learning frameworks: Tensorflow, Keras, scikit-learn

Platforms: Linux, MacOS, Windows

LANGUAGES

English (C1 level)

Vietnamese (mother tongue)

Publications

Selected papers:

- Q.-T. Phan, G. Boato, R. Caldelli, I. Amerini, "Tracking Multiple Image Sharing on Social Networks", 2019. To appear in Int. Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing.
- 2. Q.-T. Phan, G. Boato, F. G. B. De Natale, "Accurate and Scalable Image Clustering Based On Sparse Representation of Camera Fingerprint", *IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics & Security*, 2019. Early access: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/8576558.
- 3. Q.-T. Phan, C. Pasquini, G. Boato, F. G. B. De Natale, "Identifying image provenance: an analysis of mobile instant messaging apps", *Int. Workshop on Multimedia Signal Processing*, 2018.
- 4. **Q.-T. Phan**, A. Budroni, C. Pasquini and F. G. B. De Natale, "A Hybrid Approach for Multimedia Use Verification", *MediaEval*, 2016.
- 5. Q.-T. Phan, D. T. Dang-Nguyen and G. Boato and F. G. B. De Natale, "Face spoofing detection using LDP-TOP", *Int. Conference on Image Processing*, 2016.

Full list: https://goo.gl/UwwnkW

Submitted Papers

- 1. **Q.-T. Phan**, M. Vascotto, G. Boato, "Hue Modification Localization By Pair Matching", 2019. Submitted to European Signal Processing Conference. Preprint: http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.01735.
- E. Sansone, Q.-T. Phan, F. G. B. De Natale, "Coulomb Autoencoders", 2019. Submitted to International Conference on Machine Learning. Preprint: https://arxiv.org/abs/1802.03505.

Presentations

Conferences and Workshops

• Int. Conference on Image Processing, Arizona, USA	2016
• MediaEval Workshop, Hilversum, Netherlands	2016
• Int. Workshop on Multimedia Forensics and Security, Bucharest, Romania	2017
• Int. Conference on Image Analysis and Processing, Sicily, Italy	2017
• GTTI Thematic Meeting on Multimedia Signal Processing, Trento, Italy	2018

References

Upon request